小心點!
Watch it!
要點咖啡嗎?
Like some coffee?
等等,這樣不好
Wait, it's no good.
你要說點什麼才好
You have to say something.
-例如? -嗯,就像...
- Like? - Well, like...
都可以啦!
Whatever.
向巴勒斯坦問聲好
Say hello to Palestine.
怎麼向巴勒斯坦問好呢?
How, say hello to Palestine?
就像這樣
Just like that.
哈囉,巴勒斯坦
Hello, Palestine.
等等,再多說一點!
Wait. Say more.
什麼,再多點?
What, more?
我不知道,都可以,任何出現在你腦子裏的東西都可以
I dunno. Anything. Whatever pops in your head.
哈囉,巴勒斯坦
Hello, Palestine.
很高興見到你
Pleased to meet you.
什麼?
What?
你真是沒救了!
You're hopeless!
等等!我們把它做完
Wait! We'll do it over.
來吧,媽!
Coming, Mom!
見過妳的鄰居嗎?
Did you go to see your neighbors?
有啊!昨天和愛娃去看過他們而己
Yeah,I visited them yesterday with Ava.
已經七天了,大家都會過來慰問一下
For seven days, people come by to offer condolences.
從上一個到現在,已經過了很久了
It's been a long time since the last one.
在這裏它一直是個新聞
It's constantly in the news here.
媽...
Mom...
妳的下巴沾到牙膏了
you have toothpaste on your chin.
我一直在想一定去過妳那裏了
I keep thinking it could have been you.
沒,並沒有!
Well, it wasn't.
我還在傷痛之中嗎?
Am I being a pain?
對!
Yes.
是喔!妳愛我嗎?
Bu! you love me?
是呀!
Yes.
妳就吃那麼一點東西唷?
Is that all you're eating?
媽,我得走了
Mom, I gotta go.
晚點再打給妳,好嗎?
I'll call you later, OK?
拜!
Bye!
來了!媽,拜!
Coming. Bye, Mom!
- 走了! -拜,愛娃!
- I'm off! - Bye,Ava!
晚上見了
See you tonight.
-謝謝 -上前
- Thanks. - Go ahead.
哈囉!
Hello.
我們正要搜查這個區域
We're searching the area.
你們要查查超音波嗎?
Do you want to examine the ultrasound, guys?
拿給他們看,克洛伊
Show it to them, Chloé.
我正在講你!
I'm talking to you!
做好你份內的事,寶寶會被傷到
Do your job properly. The baby might be armed.
要我介紹給你嗎?
Shall I introduce you?
我的寶寶叫米卡,跟歌手一樣
My baby's named Mika, after the singer.
我們走了!做好了!
Let's go, we're done.
喂!小兄弟,回去工作!
Hey, little brother. Get back to work!
- 拜,甜心,待會見 - 拜,寶貝
- Bye, sweetie. See you later. - Bye, baby.
笨蛋!
You dork!
蘭德,把這個拿到樓上
Rand, put this upstairs.
- 他好小 -他會長大長壯的
- He's tiny! - He'll grow up strong.
媽媽要一公斤的番茄
Mom needs a kilo of tomatoes.
快點,索!
Come on, Saw!
給米卡
For Mika.
哈囉?喔!是你!
Hello? Oh, it's you!
很好,你好嗎?
Very well. And how are you?
我可以和非常令人敬重的以色列總統說話嗎?
Could I please speak to the very Honorable President of Israel?
他正在忙?
He's screwing?
我等他把事情做完
I'll hold on a few seconds till he finishes.
他做完了?
He's done?
很好!
Great!
哈囉,可敬的以色列總統先生
Hello, Mr. Honorable President of Israel.
是我,約瑟夫
It's me, Youssef.
我要告訴你這裏有多慘
I wanted to tell you that things are shitty here.
這裏,你看!
Here, look!
這裏!
Here!
你不能看到我們,我們這麼帥,真是太糟了
Too bad you can't see us. We're so handsome.
特別是我,約瑟夫
Especially me, Youssef.
等等,我找個人和你談
Wait, I'll put someone else on.
她想要知道你要煮什麼當作晚餐
She wants to know what you're cooking her for supper.
哈囉
Hello.
哈囉?
Hello?
嗨!是我
Hi, it's me.
今晚我不在家,親愛的。明天也是
I won't be home tonight, my love. Or tomorrow.
不,一個小笨蛋正在打我!
No, a little dork is hitting on me.
我想我會留下來
I think I'm going to stay.
拜!
Bye.
他掛了...
He hung HP-
他們正在放火燒移民區,快來!
They're firing on the settlement! Come on!
沒人承認該為貝特舒姆龍移民區
No one has claimed responsibility
的攻擊事件負責
for the attack on the Beit Shomron settlement.
據我們所知攻擊者備有武裝
We know that the attackers were armed
而且他們攻擊後馬上逃離現場
and that they ﬂed shortly after the attack.
飛薩仍然沒有回應
Faysa's still not answering.
有人被殺嗎?
Was anyone killed?
三個攻擊者朝居留者開槍
The three assailants fired on the settlers,
兩個人身受重傷
seriously wounding two of them.
很嚴重!
Seriously!
好吃,快要好了!
Yum, it's almost ready.
貝特舒姆龍移民區攻擊事件
The attack on the Beit Shomron settlement
是近幾週發生的第二起恐怖攻擊事件
is the second terrorist attack to take place in recent weeks.
急診醫療服務表示
The emergency medical service reports
好幾個人受重傷,
several people were seriously wounded,
但還沒公開他們的姓名
but their names have not yet been made public.
貝特舒姆龍周圍已經佈署武裝部隊
The army is being deployed around Beit Shomron.
卡蘭迪哨站加速管控
Controls will be stepped up at the Qalandia checkpoint.
蘭德,再打電話給你弟
Rand, call your brother again.
他沒接
He's not answering.
你打到影印店試試看?
Did you try the printing shop?
-外面像瘋了一樣! -聽到和攻擊有關的事嗎?
- It's crazy outside. - Hear about the attack?
當然有聽說
Of course I heard.
-兩個重傷 -情況很嚴重!
- Two wounded. - In serious condition!
我們試著聯絡你,很多次。
We tried to call you. Several times.
-燒起來了 -我喜歡它燒起來
- It's burned. - I like it burned.
像那些燒掉移民區的傢伙
Like the guys who fired on the settlement.
東西愈燒愈熱了
Things are gonna get hot!
明天,我和加薩會做些塑膠製品
Tomorrow, me and Gaza will do the plastic.
約瑟夫,你的好運用完了
Youssef, you're out of luck.
卡拉德...
Khaled...
漢姆斯和奧雷瑪...
Hamse and Oulema...
剩下的你做
you do the rest!
吃吧,兒子!
Eat, my son.
哈囉,柴德,親愛的
Hello, Ziad, my love.
他們燒掉移民區,你可以從電視上看到
They fired on the settlement.Maybe you saw it on TV.
兩個受傷,每個人都在,甚至還親眼看到
Two wounded. Everyone's here, even the visitor.
哈囉,柴德
Hello, Ziad.
克洛伊,米卡的醫生
It's Chloé, Mika's doctor.
改天,她讓我聽聽他的心跳聲
The other day, she let me listen to his heart.
親愛的,你聽到了嗎?他的心跳聲
Can you hear it, my love? It's his heart.
他聽不見的,蘭德
He can't hear it, Rand.
令人驚訝,不是嗎?
It's amazing, isn't it?
你的時間到了
Your time is up.
要換下個犯人了
It's the next prisoner's turn.
賤人
Bitch.
親愛的,那群狗東西又再一次拒絕我的申請
Darling, the dogs refused my permit request again.
但我還會再試的
But I'll try again.
我希望能早一點可以見到你
I hope I'll be able to visit you soon.
晚安,柴德
Good night, Ziad.
-媽? -晚安,柴德
- Mom? - Good night, Ziad.
我們知道你的判決就要下來了
We know your sentencing's coming up.
我們會幫你想辦法的
We're thinking of you.
武裝卡車在外面
The army trucks are outside.
她怕我們
She's scared of us.
這邊,快點
This way! Move it!
你認識鬧事的人嗎?
Do you know any fighters?
不!
No.
你有看到附近有任何武器嗎?槍?炸彈?
Did you see any weapons around? Guns? Bombs?
我沒看到
I didn't see anything.
你沒有看到任何武器嗎?
You didn't see any weapons?
不,我沒看見任何武器
No, I didn't see any weapons.
你喜歡看到移民區被攻擊嗎?
Are you glad the settlement was attacked?
妳還好嗎?
You OK'?
發生什麼事?
What's going on?
我不能說
I can't talk.
今晚我再去看妳
I'll see you tonight.
那個人說他不要給我看他的報告
The man says he won't show me his papers.
不是他根本沒有報告,
Not that he doesn't have them,
只是他不要把報告給我看
just that he doesn't want to show them to me.
所以...
So...
我想辦法冷靜下來,你知道的,
I try to stay calm, you know,
只要跟他講我只是做好份內的事,
just explain to him that I'm only doing my job,
攻擊之後,我不能讓他繼續那樣了
that after the attack, I can't let him through like that.
所以然後,札克...你認識札克嗎?
So then, Zach... You know Zach?
他問我是不是有問題
He asks me if there's a problem.
我說沒有,我可以處理
I say no, I can handle it.
但他根本不聽,就開始大吼大叫
But he doesn't listen. He starts to shout.
他極其暴怒
He went apeshit!
他要贏
He wanted to win.
他開始聚眾
He started to round up all the men.
他把他們帶到那裏
He kept them there
圍住他...
near him...
赤膊
half naked.
我都不能說什麼
I didn't say anything.
我把嘴巴閉得緊緊的
I kept my mouth shut.
我討厭做控管邊界的工作
I hate doing border control.
我比較喜歡坐在辦公室裏,或其他地方
I'd rather be in an office, or anywhere else.
我討厭哨站的責任
I hate checkpoint duty.
辭掉呀!
Quit your job.
這不是我的工作,克洛伊
It's not my job, Chloé.
我沒得選
I have no choice.
你很清楚事情沒那麼簡單
You know very well it's not that simple.
如果我的手機關機,你可以到醫院找我
You can reach me at the hospital if my mobile's off.
瑪利安,不要碰那張床。移民者在那上面辦事
Leave the bed, Mariam.The settlers fucked in it.
你他媽的聾了?我叫妳走開!
Did your mother make you deaf? Leave it!
卡里姆,你作軟塑膠的分類
Karim, you separate the soft plastic.
快點!你們這群懶鬼!
Hurry up, you bunch of slugs!
大家過來看看這個!
Guys, come see this!
看一下!
Take a look!
不,一切都很好
No, everything's fine.
不,今天沒有搜查
No, no search today.
我不行,麥克,已經打包了
I can't, Michaël. It's packed.
不,都很平靜
No, things are quiet.
沒問題,好,我可以理解
OK, fine. I understand.
要多久?
For how long?
白癡!
Idiot.
-對不起,我們要關門了! -為什麼?
- Sorry, we're closing. - Why?
診所關了
The clinic is closed.
薩菲!
Safi!
烈士是上帝所愛的人
The martyr is beloved by God!
你的血不會白流的!
Your blood won't flow in vain!
是的,媽!
Yes, Mom.
我就在樓上
I'm just upstairs.
好,我馬上下樓
Yeah, I'll be down soon.
你看起來累慘了
You look worn out.
只是缺乏睡眠罷了!
Lack of sleep, that's all.
有什麼不對勁嗎?
Is anything wrong?
都很好,媽,沒什麼大不了的
It's OK, Mom. No big deal.
妳約在什麼時候?
What time's your date?
還要一陣子
A bit later.
如果看起來一切正常要告訴我,好嗎?
Tell me if these look alright, OK?
這個呢?
These ones?
媽...
Mom...
站後面一點,我看不見!
stand back, I can't see!
喜歡嗎?
Like this?
我不知道，你沒有...
I don't know. Don't you have...
你知道，漂亮的是...
You know, the pretty ones...
圓的那對，比那些大的那對
The round ones, bigger than those.
-圓的? -是呀!
- The round ones? - Yeah.
木製的嗎?等一下,我找找
The wooden ones? Wait, I'll get them.
這對嗎?是嗎?
These ones? Right?
我知道這個表情，怎麼了？
I know that look. What's wrong?
就是這對，你真的很漂亮，媽！
Those are the ones. You're really pretty, Mom.
是嗎？
Yeah?
看著我，克洛伊
Look at me, Chloé.
妳總是杞人憂天
You always worry for nothing.
妳不要告訴我
You don't talk to me.
沒什麼好說的
I've got nothing to say.
媽媽？
Mom?
我只想看看那條河
I just want to see the river.
等一下
Wait.
那裏
There.
帶上妳的泳衣和防曬乳液
Bring along your swimsuit and sunscreen.
是到海邊的好日子
It's a great day for the beach.
一小時後，我們有更多的氣象。接下來，是今天的新聞。
We'll have more weather in an hour. Up next, it's the news.
在貝特舒姆龍猶太移民區的那起攻擊事件
The attack on the Jewish settlement in Beit Shomron
仍然還沒得到證實
is still unclaimed.
武裝部隊已經在拉姆安拉附近
For several days, the army has been carrying out
舉行很多天的大規模演習
a vast operation around Ramallah,
主要是在恐怖份子可能躲藏的難民營裏
mainly in the refugee camps where the terrorists might be hiding.
妳還好嗎?
You OK'?
- 今天妳不要工作嗎？ - 我正在聽！
- You're not working today? - I'm listening!
在亞實基倫，市議會同意要建
In Ashkelon, the municipal council approved construction
一間新的圖書館...
of a new library...
兩人受傷而且他們徹底搜查了難民營，沒人死亡！
Two wounded and they ransack the camp. Nobody died!
再想想辦法
Not for lack of trying.
另外一邊死了一個男孩，但沒人作任何評論
A boy dies on the other side, no one says anything.
他們在殖民地封鎖了攻擊的消息
They cover the attack on the colony.
這是他們的新聞，他們的工作
That's the news for them. That's their job.
一個男孩被卡車撞死，對你們以色列人來說，不是那麼重要
A boy crushed by a truck isn't important enough for you Israelis.
"我們以色列人"
"Us Israelis?"
有兩人受重傷
Two people were seriously wounded.
今晚可以看到妳嗎？
See you tonight?
不，我要值兩班，回來已經晚了
No, I have a double shift.　I'll be back late.
有可能不會再回來了，如果他們要在哨站上搞點什麼的話
Or maybe never, if they try something at the checkpoint.
愛娃...
Ava...
給妳，蘭德那裏拿的
Here, from Rand.
誰？
Who?
嗨！白人女孩
Hey, white girl.
在這個爛地方你比我們好不到那去
You're no better than us in this shit.
妳無法改變什麼的，瞭解嗎？
You couldn't have done anything different, understand?
妳正在做什麼？
What are you doing?
快點，那個給我，把它給我！
Come on, give me that. Give it to me!
-你要去那裏？ -上車
- Where you going? - Get in.
這些也要
These ones too.
-我的朋友! -阿曼德,還好嗎?
- My friend! - lmad, what's up?
阿曼德
lmad!
到這裏來!
Come here!
我們走
Let's go.
他帶他的醫生來給我們看
He's showing off his doctor!
你好嗎?
How are you?
你開了整個難民營裏最好的車子
You drive the nicest car in the whole camp!
而且他還假裝不認得我們
And he pretends not to know us.
他現在變成導遊了！
He's become a tourist guide!
他的車子閃亮閃亮的，不可能再更亮了
His car's shiny, shiny. Couldn't get any shinier.
這可能對我們有用唷！
It might be useful to us.
可能對我們會有幫助
It could help us out.
可能非常有幫助
It could be very helpful.
不再多喝點茶嗎？
Have some more tea!
明天見，我的朋友！
See you tomorrow, my friend!
-別生病了! -或輪胎沒氣
- Don't get sick!　- Or have a flat!
嗨!阿曼德
Hi, lmad.
好呀!你可以過來
OK, you can come over.
拜!
Bye.
克洛伊，我要告訴妳
Chloé, I have to talk to you.
等一下
Two seconds.
怎麼了？
What's up?
這是什麼？
What's this?
我不能把它們丟掉
I couldn't throw them out.
好極了！你自己去貼海報的嗎？
Bravo! Did you paste them yourself?
-聽著，我在那... -妳正在搞什麼?
- Look, I was there... - What the hell are you doing?
妳不能只做份內的工作就好
You can't just do as you please here.
我是個醫生，能置身事外嗎？
I'm a doctor, stay out of it?
是呀！完全正確！
Exactly, yeah.
克洛伊正在忙！
Chloé's busy!
今天是薩菲的生日！
It's Safi's birthday!
蘭德！
Rand!
這裏還有點規矩，妳知道的！
There are rules here. You know that.
妳不能隨心所欲，為所欲為
You can't do anything you want.
妳要冷靜一點，做好自己的工作
You have to keep a cool head, do your work.
他的血就在我的鞋子上
His blood was on my shoes.
是呀！下一次你要做什麼？
Yeah? What'll you do next time?
別擔心！
Don't worry.
妳還有嗎？
Do you have any more?
把那些丟到垃圾桶裏
Throw those in the garbage.
他叫什麼？
What was his name again?
約瑟夫
Youssef.
他是個小傻子
He was a little dork.
小什麼？
A little what?
小笨蛋！
A little punk!
嗨，小可愛！
Hi there, darling!
-你有鑰匙嗎？　-有!
- Do you have your keys? - Yes.
因為過完週末妳要自己開門
Because you open up after the weekend.
-我可以載妳一程？ -不，我自己用走的
- Can I give you a lift? - No, I'll walk.
-確定？　-是呀!
- Sure?　- Yeah.
克洛伊 ！
Chloé!
妳看見那顆星嗎？
You see that star?
最亮的那顆？
The brightest one?
事實上，它不是一顆星
It's not a star, in fact.
那是以色列的控制塔
It's an Israeli control tower.
他們在每個地方監視我們
They spy on us everywhere.
他是巴基斯坦人
He's Palestinian!
他進了準決賽
He's in the semifinals.
-妳好嗎？ -很好！
- How are you? - Good.
-忙嗎？ -普通
- Busy day? - The usual.
你有身份證嗎？
Do you have ID?
你打哪來?
Where are you from?
放下你的香煙！
Put out your cigarette!
就在這個村子?不再更遠?
Just to the village?  No farther?
對，我們會在入夜前回來
Yes. We'll be back before nightfall.
看看我能做什麼
I'll see what I can do.
我相信妳
I'm trusting you.
晚安！
Good night.
-八個小時 -是呀！
- Eight hours. - Yes.
不能再多
No more.
謝啦！
Thanks.
妳確定嗎？
Are you sure?
我不知道我們在哪？全都是希伯來文
I don't know where we are. It's all in Hebrew.
這裏！
Here!
絕不！
No way.
-這裏！ -閉嘴!
- Here! - Shut up!
這裏是我們以前吃東西的地方
This is where we used to eat.
媽!爸!
Mom, Dad,
艾哈邁德、鮑娜
Ahmed, Fauna,
歐瑪和瑪利亞
Omar and Mariam.
和妳?
And you?
我坐在媽媽旁邊
I sat next to Mom.
浴室在這裏
The bathroom was here.
把石頭放下來
Leave the rocks alone!
你要把整個聖地都裝到你的袋子裏去嗎？你這個白癡!
You put the entire Holy Land in your bag, you nut!
別管他
Leave him be.
謝謝!謝謝!
Thank you, thank you!
好了！我們走吧！
OK, let's go.
你有什麼問題？
What's your problem?
妳認為妳很偉大嗎？
You think you're so great, huh?
為什麼妳就是要帶我們到這來？
Why did you bring us here anyway?
妳是不是有什麼不能取代的東西被偷了嗎？
Have you ever had something stolen that you can't replace?
妳喜歡這種只能看，不能碰的東西嗎？
Would you like to see it, but not be able to touch it?
所以，妳現在感覺好一點了嗎？媽？
So, do you feel better now, Mom?
幫妳想起妳所失去的，這樣很爽嗎？是不是？
Helps you remember what you've lost. Great, huh?
妳可以告訴妳兒子，我們有多麼失敗，真棒！
You? You can tell your son what losers we are. Super!
我要留在這裏，我喜歡在這，其他人也是
I'm staying. I like being here.　The others too.
你不可能快樂的，那是你的問題
You can never be happy, that's your problem.
看！
Look.
我們拿到的特別許可證，得要感謝妳那個白人朋友
The special authorization we got thanks to your white friend.
看一看！
Look at it!
我們要那個東西才能回到自己的村子
We need that to visit our own village.
妳媽的出生的
Your mother's birthplace.
讓妳很快樂，那才是問題！
It makes you happy. That's the problem.
妳想錯了！
You thought wrong.
-一切都順利吧？ -是呀！
- Did it go alright? - Yeah.
-妳把他們都帶回來了？ -是呀！別擔心！
- You brought them all back? - Yeah, don't worry.
我和艾塔瑪談過了，他正要去特拉維夫
I spoke to ltamar. He's going to Tel Aviv.
不，不是我
No. Not me.
不是今晚
Not tonight.
我好累
I'm so tired.
什麼？
What?
這不是妳的戰爭
It's not your war.
我這裏沒有很多
We don't have much here.
但我們正在受苦
But we're suffering.
至少讓我們擁有那個
Let us have that, at least.
妳不能在這裏只出現一下子而已
You can't just turn up here
而是要和我們像那樣玩玩！
and play around with our shit like that.
它不是妳的
It's not yours.
請到阿哈亞醫院！
The Al Hayat hospital, please!
我不能再靠近了，到處都是哨站
I can get you close, but there are checkpoints everywhere.
我發誓，他們都像獵犬一樣
I swear, they're like hunting dogs.
他們在營區裏追踪到一支運動人士的手機
They targeted an activist cell in the camp.
他們正在找任何可疑的東西
They're searching everything.
我必須在這裏停下來
I have to stop here.
妳用走的比較快
You'll be faster on foot anyway.
我妹要生了，我一定要到醫院裏去
My sister's in labor. We have to get to the hospital.
拜託！
Please.
我也不要在這裏
I don't want to be here either.
我也寧願到別的地方去
I'd rather be somewhere else too.
她不能從哨站轉送過去！
She can't deliver at the checkpoint!
今天那一隊上場打球？
Who's playing today?
巴賽隆納
Barcelona.
巴賽隆納正在打？　你是巴賽隆納的粉絲嗎？
Barcelona's playing? Are you a Barcelona fan?
我也是！
Me too!
米卡要出來了！
Mika's coming!
八公分了！
Eight centimeters.
流太多血了！
Too much blood.
你最喜歡那個球員？
Who's your favorite player?
我最喜歡普悠兒
Me, it's Puyol.
世上最好的防守球員
Best defender in the world.
他從未失分
He never scores.
他防守到自己倒地，拜託，老兄！
He defends till he drops. Please, man!
我妹妹不能在這裏生孩子
My sister can't give birth here.
拜託！
Please.
那是妳家的屁事！
What's your fucking problem?
-克洛伊，待在我身邊　-我不會離開妳的
- Chloé, stay with me! - I won't leave you.
走
Go.
-妳可以嗎？　-可以，你走吧！
- Will you be OK? - Yeah, you go.
好，他準備好了！
OK, he's ready.
就是這樣，繼續！
That's it, keep going!
就是這樣
That's it!
用力！用力！用力！
Push, push, push!
讓出通路！
Clear the way!
讓她過！
Let her through!
你現在可以走了
You can leave now.
沒時間了
There's no time.
如果他們還有人在另外一邊，我可以讓它過來
If they have someone on the other side, I can get it through.
為什麼？我要這樣！
Why? I want to do it!
嗨！
Hi.
門關起來
Shut the door.
我有消息要給蘭德
I have news for Rand.
我從法院那裏接到一通電話
I got a call from the court.
柴德被求處二十五年徒刑
Ziad was sentenced to 25 years.
小老鼠，小老鼠，妳失去了妳的寶貝
Little rat, little rat, you've lost your babies
妳在這裏已經一無所有了，小老鼠，小老鼠！
There's nothing for you here, little rat, little rat!
-找妳的寶貝,蘭德? -或是妳丈夫呢?
- Looking for your baby, Rand? - Or your husband?
那裏
There.
好了！
We're done.
妳今天很忙嗎？
Do you have a big day today?
會做到很晚嗎？
Do you finish late?
如果妳快點回來，他就不會死了！
If you'd come sooner, he wouldn't be dead.
我就不會是隻老鼠了，只要妳快一點回來
I wouldn't be a rat if you'd come sooner.
小蕩婦！
Little slut!
一下子和阿拉伯人，一下子和猶太人
Now with the Arabs, now with the Jews!
妳對他們怎麼說我們的？
What will you tell them about us?
那一種人比較好？猶太人還是阿拉伯人？
Who tastes better, the Jews or the Arabs?
喂，克洛伊？那一種人呢？
Huh, Chloé? Who?
回家吧！妳這隻骯髒的母狗！
Go back home, you dirty bitch!
他很快就回來
He'll be back soon.
你還好吧？
You OK?
你確定？
You sure?
小心！
Watch it!
-要點咖啡嗎？ -好呀！
- Like some coffee? - Yes.
這是妳點的，糖！
Here you are. Sugar.
是的，媽，我還活著
Yes, mom, I'm alive.
請待在直線裏！
Stay in a straight line, please!
我，蘭德-薩巴哈，
I, Rand Sabbah,
寧願以死亡之姿而存在，而不願意活著卻看不見
prefer to exist in death than to live unseen.
將不再有人可以奪走我存在的權利
No one will ever again take away my right to exist.
我不是石牆，我不是岩石
I am not a wall. I am not a rock.
當我和我的寶貝團聚時，我會高高的抬起頭來
I hold my head high as I go to join my baby.
我的血，泣訴著我的故事
My blood, tell my story.
給所有我愛的人，我問候你們
To all those I love, I greet you.
我希望能在天堂中再看到你們
I hope to meet you again in heaven.
求主垂憐
Inch'Allah.
一棵很大的樹...
A very big tree...
和另一棵，小一點的...
and another, smaller one...
在它的旁邊長大
that's growing next to it.
獻給我的兒子
TO MY SONS